Southwest Folklore Center Sound Disc Collection, 1945-1987
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Eres tu todo -- Un aventon, Cano, Jesús García, 1982; Mexico, Discos DC de Mexico, 1982; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Jesús García Cano accompanied by Mariachi Oro de Mexico... Produced by Jesús García Cano... Picture of performer on record label... Eres tu todo -- Un aventon --; SWF 95.18/D.33
- Como yo te quiero -- Amor se dice cantando, Cano, Jesús García, 1982; Mexico, Discos DC de Mexico, 1982; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Jesús García Cano R.A.D.D.A. accompanied by Mariachi Oro de México... Produced by Jesús García Cano... Picture of Jesús García Cano on record label... Como yo te quiero -- Amor se dice cantando --; SWF 95.18/D.34
- Bario pobre -- La bengansa de preso, Los Nuevos del Norte de Valentin y Jose, Discos Marinero; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Los Nuevos del Norte de Valentin y Jose... Bario pobre -- La bengansa del preso --; SWF 95.18/D.35
- Soñar es mi destino -- Triste despedida, Los Cardenales del Norte de Tony Muñoz, Nogales-Sonora, Discos Nogales; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Los Cardenales del Norte... Soñar es mi destino -- Triste despedida --; SWF 95.18/D.36
- Travesuras de mujer -- Mintiendo eres feliz, Dueto Sopresa, Nogales-Sonora, Discos Nogales; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Dueto Sopreso con: Los Cinco del Norte... Travesuras de mujer -- Mintiendo eres feliz --; SWF 95.18/D.37
- Que caso tiene -- Que cancion te canto, Los Microbios de Naco Sonora, Mexico, Discos Laser; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Los Microbios de Naco Sonora... Que caso tiene -- Que cancion te canto --; SWF 95.18/D.38
- Soy puro norteño -- Mi nave, Jose y Alejo, Mexico, Discos Indio; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Jose y Alejo con el Conjunto Rio Yaqui... Soy puro norteño -- Mi nave --; SWF 95.18/D.39
- Sin sabor -- Extraño mucho a mi amor, La Reaccion, Megatino; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by La Reaccion... Sin sabor -- Extraño mucho a mi amor --; SWF 95.18/D.40
- Floresita adorada -- Signo fatal, Manjarrez, Raul, Mexico, Discos DC; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Raul Manjarrez con el Mariachi Tecalitlan... Una prducción de Jesús García Cano...Floresitas adorada -- Signo fatal --; SWF 95.18/D.41
- Prohibido -- Priviligio, Manjarrez, Raúl, Mexico, Discos DC de Mexico; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Raúl Manjarrez con el Mariachi Los Polmeros de Ramiro Jauregui (Priviligio) and el Mariachi Los Rancheros de Jose Santos (Prohibido)... Prohibido -- Priveligio --; SWF 95.18/D.42
- Mas exitos con Jesús García Cano, Cano, Jesús García, Mexico, Discos DC de Mexico; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Jesús García Cano con el Mariachi Nuevo Tecalitlan... Una producción de Jacobo Palu... Record cover has picture of Jesús García Cano... Muñeqita -- Jugando --; SWF 95.18/D.43
- El borriquito -- Te quiero asi, Benitez, Blanquita, Mexico, Discos DC de Mexico; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Blanquita Benitez con La Banda de Mauro Martin J.R.... Una produccíon de Jesús García Cano... Record cover has picture of Blanquita Benitez... El borriquito -- Te quiero asi --; SWF 95.18/D.44
- El Triunfador, Cano, Jesús García, Mexico, Discos DC de Mexico; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by El Triunfador Jesús García Cano con el Mariachi Oro de México... Record cover has picture of Cano on front and words to 'Mi ciudad Nogales' by Ignacio Cienfuegos Heredía on back... Sinceramente tuyo -- Mi ciudad Nogales --; SWF 95.18/D.45
- Fruto de amor -- Cositas, Grupo Impala de Naco Sonora, Naco-Sonora, Mexico, Discos Naco, Sonora; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Grupo Impala de Naco Sonora... Record cover has picture of performers on the on the front and... Fruto de amor -- Cositas --; SWF 95.18/D.46
- Que importa la distancia -- Te sigo queriendo, Grupo Imapala de Naco Sonora, Naco-Sonora, Mexico, Discos Naco, Sonora; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Grupo Imapala de Naco Sonora... Record cover has picture of group on front cover... Brief history of group on the back... Que importa la distancia -- Te sigo queriendo --; SWF 95.18/D.47
- Ya piso paso -- Rebelde del amor, Alejandro, Discos Disko; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Alejandro... Picture of Alejandro on record cover... Ya piso paso -- Rebelde del amor --; SWF 95.18/D.48
- Corridos Regionales con Jesus Maria Grijalva, Grijalva, Jesús Maria, Hermosillo Sonora, Mexico, Arriola; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Jesus Maria Grijalva... Picture of performer on record cover... Recuerdo a la caridad -- Paristas de Nacozari --; SWF 95.18/D.49
- Prenda querida -- Ya no vuelvo querer, Silva, Enrique, Culiacan, Sin. México, Discos Constelación; 1 sound disc, anlog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; NOTES: Performed by Enrique Silva... Picture of performer on record cover... Prenda querida -- Ya no vuelvo querer --; SWF 95.18/D.50
- Paisaje Musical Sonorense, Banda de Musica del Estado, Estado de Sonora; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; NOTES: Album cover describes the group and the music it plays (in spanish)... This is a final volume of a six volume series with a collection from various composers... Saludo a suaqui (Eduardo C. Gulliver) -- Flor de capomo (Dominio Publico) -- San Isidro (Silvestre Rodriguez) -- Tu mirada (Silvestre Rodriguez) -- Baille de diablo (Gildardo Vazquez) -- El jorullo (Federico Bustillos) -- El limoncito (Silvestre Rodriguez) -- A mi patria Mexico (Federico Bustillos) -- No se por que te quiero (Manuel S. Acuña)--; SWF 95.25/D.1
- Valses Inéditos de Rodolfo Campodónico Vol.2, Banda de Musica del Estado, Gobierno del Estado de Sonora, Mexico; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; NOTES: Performed by Banda de musica del Estado... Director: Capitan 1ro. Carlos Ramirez Paredes... All performed by Rodolfo Campodónico... Constanza -- Crucita -- Amando -- Catalina --; SWF 95.25/D.2
- Valses Inéditas de Rudolfo Campodónico Vol.1, Banda de Musica del Estado, Gobierno del Estado de Sonora, Mexico; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; NOTES: Performed by Rudolfo Campodónico... Recuerdo a amalia -- En tu dia -- Natalia -- Laura --; SWF 95.25/D.3
- Down in the willow -- Worried man blues, Mainer, Wade and Zeke Morris / The Carter Family, Camden, N.J., RCA-Victor Records; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; NOTES: Collection of Smoky Mountain ballads... Five records by nine artists/groups collected by John A. Lomax... Introduction and description of songs by John A. Lomax... Performers include Wade Mainer and Zeke Morris on side one and The Carter Family on side two... Down in the willow (Mainer and Morris, singing with violin, guitar, and banjo) -- Worried man blues (The Carter Family, singing with autoharp and guitar) --; SWF 95.31/D.1
- On a cold winter night -- Ida Red, J.E. Mainer's Mountaineers / Gid Tanner and his Skillet Lickers, Camden, N.J., RCA-Victor Records; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; NOTES: Collection of Smokey Mountain ballads... Five records by nine artists or groups... Collected by John A. Lomax... Introduction and description of songs by John A. Lomax... Performers include: J.E. Mainer's Mountaineers on side one and Gid Tanner and his Skillet Lickers on side two... On a cold winter night (J.E. Mainer's Mountaineers, singing by Wade Mainer) -- Ida Red (Gid Tanner and his Skillet Lickers, string band with singing) --; SWF 95.31/D.2
- The east Virginia blues -- Cumberland Mountain deer race, The Carter Family / Uncle Dave Macon, Camden, N.J., RCA-Victor Records; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; NOTES: Collection of Smokey Mountain ballads... Five records by nine artists/groups... Collected by John A. Lomax... Introduction and description of songs by John A. Lomax... Performers include: The Carter Family on side one and Uncle Dave Macon on side two... The east Virginia blues (The Carter Family, singing with guitar and auto harp) -- Cumberland Mountain deer race (Uncle Dave Macon, singing and banjo) --; SWF 95.31/D.3
- Intoxicated rat -- Chittlin' cookin' time in Cheatham County, Dixon Brothers / Arthur Smith Trio, Camden, N.J., RCA-Victor Records; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; NOTES: Collection of Smoky Mountain ballads... Five records by nine artists/groups... Collected by John A. Lomax... Introduction and description of songs by John A. Lomax... Performers include Dixon Brothers on side one and Arthur Smith Trio on side two... Intoxicated rat (Dixon Brothers, singing with guitars) -- Chittlin' cookin' in Cheatham County (Arthur Smith Trio, singing with violin and guitars) --; SWF 95.31/D.4
- Riding on that train forty-five -- Darling Corey, Mainer, Wade / Monroe Brothers, Camden, N.J., RCA-Victor Records; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; NOTES: Collection of Smoky Mountain ballads... Five records by nine artists/groups... Collected by John A. Lomax... Introduction and description of songs by John A. Lomax... Performers include: Wade Mainer, Zeke Morris, Steve Ledford on side one and the Monroe Brothers on side two... Riding on that train forty-five (Wade Mainer, Zeke Morris,and Steve Ledford, singing with violin, guitar, and banjo) -- Darling Corey (Monroe Brothers, Charles and Bill) --; SWF 95.31/D.5
- Contestación a “Y” -- Clases de musica, Lalo Guerrero, Monterey Park Calif., Colonial Records 45-378; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.20/D.1
- Mujer cualquiera -- El timido, Lalo Guerrero, Monterey Park Calif., Colonial Records 444; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.20/D.2
- Llego mu crudo el Greñudo -- Busco una novia, Lalo Guerrero, Monterey Park Calif., Colonial Records 448; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.20/D.3
- Soldado raso -- No naci pa’ soldado, Lalo Guerrero, Monterey Park Calif., Colonial Records 553; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.20/D.4
- Malas jugadas -- La flaca, Lalo Guerrero, Monterey Park Calif., Colonial Records 547; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.20/D.5
- Nunca jamás -- Mentira, Lalo Guerrero, Monterey Park Calif., Colonial Records 556; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.20/D.6
- Ricordate Marcelino -- Pancho Claus, Lalo Guerrero, Los Angeles, Calif., L and M Records 45-1003; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.20/D.7
- La ultima carrera del tigre (El tigre vs. la mora) -- Si no me lo das, Los Principales de Sonora, Tucson Ariz., OHS II Video and Music Productions; 1 sound disk, stereo, 45 rpm, 7 in.; “La ultima carrera del tigre” was written by Oscar H. Stevens, and Oscar H. Stevens, Jr.; SWF 97.27/D.1
- El moro de cumpas (Leonardo Llanes [i.e. Leonardo Yáñez]) -- El presidiario 13 (Jose Navarro), Leonardo Yáñez, Jose Navarro, Norwalk, Calif., Mares Records MA-039; 1 sound disk, stereo, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.29/D.1
- “El moro de cumpas” (Leonardo Yáñez) -- “Con nada me pagas” (J.A. Jiménez), Leonardo Yáñez, J.A. Jiménez, [S.l.] Del Valle Records DV 871; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; SWF 97.29/D.2
- El caporal [sound recording], Eduardo Fierro, México, D.F., Discos Laser, LAS 076; 1 sound disk, 33-1/3 rpm, 12 in.; CONTENTS: [side A] Que quieres que te diga -- El pavido navido -- Justicia ranchera -- El palo verdo -- Peregrina -- [side B] El naufrago -- Puerta de oro -- Los indios con Obregón -- El jilguerito -- Rinconcitos de Sonora.; SWF 97.32/D.1
- Indian songs of the Southwest: gems for collectors, Taos, N.M., J.S. Candelario; 4 sound disks, 78 rpm, 10 in.; CONTENTS: Apache songs: Mountain spirits dance -- Sun greeting ceremony -- Hopi songs: Butterfly dance -- War dance -- Navajo songs: Yeibichai -- Squaw dance -- Taos songs: War dance -- Moonlight song.; SWF 97.34/D.1
- Favorite music: including songs of the Southwest, Tucson Boys’ Choir, Hollywood, Calif., C.P. MacGregor; 3 sound disks, 78 rpm, 10 in.; “Presented by the Elks Lodge 385, Tucson, Arizona” CONTENTS: Home on the range -- Cool water -- Silver on the sage -- Blue shadows on the trail -- Holiday for strings -- Estrellita.; SWF 97.34/D.2
- Sage brush and sand -- Sleepy Lincoln town (with Bob Bruce), Don Paull’s Canyon Caravan, Bob Bruce, Albuquerque, N.M., Sun Recording Co., BG-103; SWF 97.34/D.3
- The O.K. Corral -- Song of life, Griz Green’s Arizonans, Phoenix, Ariz., Liberty Bell 45-9008; 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Story of the gunfight in Tombstone at the O.K. Corral on Oct. 26, 1881.; SWF 97.34/D.5
- Navajo creation chants, Cambridge, Mass., Peabody Museum of Harvard University; 5 sound disks, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; CONTENTS: Song of the twins -- Song of the red ants -- Tobacco song -- Song of the coyote who stole the fire -- A song of the flood -- A song of the flood -- “There are no people” -- Sweathouse song -- Sweathouse song -- Song of the sun -- Hogahn song -- The song of the Earth Spirit -- “Where the stars were made” -- “When they saw each other” -- The heroes search for their father -- The heroes greet the dawn and the darkness -- the heroes arrive at the sun’s house -- Wind song -- The heroes kill the giant -- Song of the movement of creation -- Song of the talking god -- Songs of Anthltahni -- Old age song -- It shows my way -- I am on my way -- A song of the dawn -- The last song of the dawn.; SWF 97.34/D.6
- American Indian music of the Southwest, Ethnic Folkways Library P420); 1 sound disk, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; SWF 97.34/D.7
- The old Chisholm trail: songs of the American Southwest / by Tony Kramer, Tony Kraber, New York, N.Y., Keynote Recordings 104; 3 sound disks, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; CONTENTS: The tenderfoot -- Blood on the saddle -- The boll weevil song -- Green grow the lilacs -- Whiskey, rye whiskey -- The old Chisholm trail. -- The next big river -- Kansas boys.; SWF 97.37/D.1
- Ella [sound recording], Joe Venuti; Mary Venuti, Cactus Wren CW 45-101; CONTENTS: Side A: Ella -- Side B: Spanish eyes; 97.62/D.1
- Los Payadores del Pueblo, v. 3, Payadores del Pueblo, 1 sound disk, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Recording of Pueblo High School estudiantina singing group, recorded ca. 1969.; 97.67/D.1
- Viva el fuerte; El prófugo de Sonora, Ismael Armenta conla Banda Perla Azul del Fuerte, 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in. Source: Discos Arca AR-003; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.1
- Que bonita navidad; El corrido de año nuevo, Juan Derecho y Sus Comanches, 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in. Source: DC 143; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.2
- Bala perdida; La mula bronca; El corrido de año nuevo; Lo supe por Lupe, El Ideal, 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in. Source: DC 105; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.3
- El asesino; Mis amigos la conocen, Country Mingo “The Outlaw”, 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in. Source: Falcon A2243; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.4
- El corrido de Pedro Aviles; La muerte de un cadete, Los huracanes del norte, 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in. Source: Luna 311; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.5
- Bajo el cielo de Jalisco; El corrido de Ayutla, Gonzalo Pérez con el Mariachi Ayutla, 1 sound disk, 45 rpm, 7 in. Source: Discos America DA 011; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.6
- Roberto Ruiz; El boracho 007, Gavilanes, Falcon 1795; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.7
- Lucio Cabañas; Quintero y Mendoza, Los amarradores del Norte, Tuco n ARA/1479; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.8
- La banda del carro rojo; El contrabando del Paso, Los alegres de Teran, Caytronics CY 8188; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.9
- El contrabando de Nogales; Corrido de Patricia Hearst, Los Magnifikos, Falcon A-2080; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.10
- Las drogas; Contrabando y robo, Los Tigres del Norte, Discos Fama FA-475; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.11
- Chavela (Jesus Cardenas); El corrido de Juanito, Al Hurricane, Hurricane 45-7043; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.12
- Despedida con mariachi; El crimen de Chihuahua, Los Cadetes de Linares, Disco Dica 883; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.13
- Rogelio Garza Tijerina; Mujer sin nombre, Los Tremendos Gavilanes de Monterrey, Discos Larga Vida 5135; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.14
- Corrido de Agustin Lara / Los Aguilar; Corrido de Agustin Lara / Trio Tariacuri, Los Aguilar and Trio Tariacuri, RCA Victor 76-3289; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.15
- Jesús Maldonado; Cuando Vuelan las gaviotas, José Alfredo Jiménez, RCA Victor 76-2912; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.16
- Pensando en ti; La banda del marquis negro, Los Zafiros del Norte, RCA SP-5947; donated by James S. Griffith; 97.70/D.17
- El corrido de Juan Martha; La vuidita, Los Huracanes del Norte, Luna L-230; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.18
- El cochesito; Rodrigo Martinez, Los dos Gilbertos, Falcon 2204; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.19
- Maquina 501; Paloma blanca, Brown Express, Gamma G-1671; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.20
- De mañana en Adelante; Me voy pal otro lado, Gerardo Reyes, Gamma G-1671; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.21
- Mi lindo rio grande / Alberto Barrera y Los Conquistadores; El mexicotejano / Jesús Garcia y Chepe Solis [y Los Conquistadores], Alberto Barrera y Los Conquistadores; Jesús Garcia y Chepe Solis [y Los Conquistadores], Cobest RGS 101; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.22
- El corrido de los mojados; Quedo pendiente una boda, Los Alegres de Teran, Caytronics CY 8242; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.23
- Joaquin Murrieta; Jesús Cadena, Lydia Mendoza, Norteño 387; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.24
- Pistoleros de Chihuahua; Sombreretillo, Grupo Pacifico, Garmex GM 2001; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.25
- (El corrido de) la prision de Santa Fe; Mi madrecita, Al Hurricane con El Mariachi Nuevo Tapatio de Pedro Sepulveda, Hurricane 45-7103; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.26
- Historia de un millonario; Corrido de Chuy Pruneda, Los Cachorros, CRC 4; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.27
- El adios del soldado; Siete Leguas, Vicente Fernandez y Felipe Arriaga, Caytronics CY 8144; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.28
- No volvere; De Texas a California, Carmen Luna, Almex TM-091383; donated by James S. Griffith.; 97.70/D.29
- Old Shep / Bill Miegs; San Antonio Rose / Dean Armstrong and the Arizona Dance Hands, CSR-2003; Southern Arizona International Livestock Association and Pima County Fair Souvenir, 1970; donated by James S. Griffith; 98.2/D.1